Finding Aid for the Adolph Altman Collection of Photographs PASC-M.0109
UCLA Library Special Collections
Adolph Altman Collection of Photographs
1937-1938
UCLA Library Special Collections
Altman, Adolph
PASC-M.0109
1 Linear Feet
Photographs of musicians, including Harold Arlen, E. Y. Harburg, Frank Black, Irving Caesar, Abram Chasins, George M. Cohan, Walter Damrosch, Duke Ellington, Leopold Godowsky, Ferde Grofe, David Guion, Fritz Kreisler, Albert Spalding, and Rudy Vallee.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Acquisition Information
Gift, Adolph Altman, 1992
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9948557823606533
Biography
No information about Adolph Altman is available.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of photographs of musicians, including Harold Arlen, E. Y. Harburg, Frank Black, Irving Caesar, Abram Chasins, George M. Cohan, Walter Damrosch, Duke Ellington, Leopold Godowsky, Ferde Grofe, David Guion, Fritz Kreisler, Albert Spalding, and Rudy Vallee.
- Harold Arlen and E.Y. Harburg, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Frank Black, 1938; B/W, 8 x 10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Irving Caesar, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents note
  ASCAP
- Irving Caesar, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Irving Caesar, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Irving Caesar, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Abram Chasins, 1938; B/W, 8 x 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- George M. Cohan, 1938; B/W, 8 x 10 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- George M. Cohan, 1938; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Walter Damrosch, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Walter Damrosch, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 11)
  N.B.C. Orchestra
- Walter Damrosch, 1938; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Duke Ellington, 1938; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Cotton Club (?)
- Duke Ellington, 1938; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Leopold Godowsky, 1938; B/W, 6 1/2 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Leopold Godowsky, 1938; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Leopold Godowsky, 1938 [?]; B/W, 8 x 10 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Ferde Grofe, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Ferde Grofe, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Bowl Manhattan
- Ferde Grofe, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Ferde Grofe, 1938 [1937?]; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Conducting
- David Guion, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Home on the Range
- Fritz Kreisler, 1938; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Fritz Kreisler, 1938; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Albert Spalding, 1938; B/W, 8 x 10, mounted (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Rudy Vallee, 1938; B/W, 8 x 10 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Unidentified man and female child, B/W, 8 x 10 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- George Gershwin's funeral, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Temple Emanuel, N.Y. - shown: Gene Buck, president of ASCAP and Mayor LaGuardia
- George Gershwin's funeral, 1937; B/W, 8 x 10 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Temple Emanuel, N.Y.